Two Hundred
Years Later
Kanto
Two Hundred
Years Later
Kanto
Two Hundred
Years Later
Kanto
All hail His Majesty, the Emperor of Delight, fifth of his line!
大歓喜帝陛下
第５代皇帝
ご即位 おめでとうございます
Hail!
おめでとうございます！
Now, my emperor, the people
eagerly await your appearance!
それでは 大歓喜帝陛下
民が 今か 今かと
待っておりますゆえ
Hearken!
民よ聞け！ これより
我が神聖サクラ王朝は
Our Lord has taken the reins of the
Holy Cherry Blossom Empire as our fifth sovereign!
第５代皇帝陛下により
その政事を
統べられることとあいなった！
ここに民に宣言する！
Thus I proclaim as his herald!
神聖サクラ王朝 第５代皇帝陛下は
From this purification, the fifth emperor of the
Holy Cherry Blossom Empire shall hence be known as
このよき ことほぎの日より
大歓喜帝とあいなる
the Emperor of Delight!
最初に拍手を
やめた者から100人までを
The first hundred to stop clapping
shall be the sacrifices for this ceremony!
この ことほぎの日の
いけにえとする！
From
the
New
World
From
the
New
World
From
the
New
World
From
the
New
World
From
the
New
World
From
the
New
World
From
the
New
World
From
the
New
World
From
the
New
World
え～ じゃあ 今日は青沼君
Aonuma-kun, please.
Okay.
はい 今から180年ほど前の話
Karma Demon
There lived a boy in the village 180 years ago.
村に１人の少年が 住んでいた
とても そうめいな子供だったが
１つの欠点があった
He was a boy of great intelligence, but he had one weakness.
その欠点は 成長するにつれ
As he grew into a man, it became increasingly clear to everyone.
次第に誰の目にも
明らかなものになってきた
少年は
自らの頭の良さを誇るあまり
The boy mocked all things around him so as to glorify his own intellect.
あらゆるものを
小バカにしていたのだ
学校や村の大人たちから
教わることを
He pretended to listen carefully to all the things that the school and the village’s adults taught him,
表面的には
よく 聞くふりをしていたが
but the important lessons never touched his heart.
大切な教訓は 決して
彼の心に届いてはいなかった
傲慢は 業の種をまく
Pride plants the seeds of bad karma.
孤独だけが 彼の友人になり
話し相手になった
Solitude was his only friend and confidant.
Solitude brings the seeds of bad karma to fruit.
孤独は 業の苗床になる
思考は とめどなく
業をはびこらせてゆく
His bad karma grew rampant like vines, watered by his thoughts.
Unbeknownst to him, the boy’s karma spiraled further out of control,
そして 少年は
知らず知らずのうちに
業を積み重ね
and eventually he lost all his humanity.
次第に 人間ではないもの
業魔へと変わっていったのだ
He had turned into a karma demon.
The karma demon realized at last that his existence was for the worse of this world.
業魔は ようやく
自分が この世に存在しては
いけないことに気づいた
業魔は
この世に存在してはいけない
Karma demons ought not to walk this world.
そのことを悟って
Now that he knew it, he quietly walked his body to the bottom of a lake.
ひっそりと
湖の底に姿を消したのだった
Asahina Satoru
Amano Reiko
Itou Mamoru
Asahina Satoru
Amano Reiko
Itou Mamoru
Asahina Satoru
Amano Reiko
Itou Mamoru
Asahina Satoru
Amano Reiko
Itou Mamoru
Asahina Satoru
Amano Reiko
Itou Mamoru
Asahina Satoru
Amano Reiko
Itou Mamoru
Asahina Satoru
Amano Reiko
Itou Mamoru
Asahina Satoru
Amano Reiko
Itou Mamoru
Asahina Satoru
Amano Reiko
Itou Mamoru
Asahina Satoru
Amano Reiko
Itou Mamoru
Asahina Satoru
Amano Reiko
Itou Mamoru
Asahina Satoru
Amano Reiko
Itou Mamoru
Asahina Satoru
Amano Reiko
Itou Mamoru
Asahina Satoru
Amano Reiko
Itou Mamoru
Asahina Satoru
Amano Reiko
Itou Mamoru
Asahina Satoru
Amano Reiko
Itou Mamoru
Asahina Satoru
Amano Reiko
Itou Mamoru
Asahina Satoru
Amano Reiko
Itou Mamoru
Asahina Satoru
Amano Reiko
Itou Mamoru
Asahina Satoru
Amano Reiko
Itou Mamoru
Asahina Satoru
Amano Reiko
Itou Mamoru
Asahina Satoru
Amano Reiko
Itou Mamoru
Asahina Satoru
Amano Reiko
Itou Mamoru
Asahina Satoru
Amano Reiko
Itou Mamoru
Asahina Satoru
Amano Reiko
Itou Mamoru
Asahina Satoru
Amano Reiko
Itou Mamoru
Asahina Satoru
Amano Reiko
Itou Mamoru
Asahina Satoru
Amano Reiko
Itou Mamoru
Asahina Satoru
Amano Reiko
Itou Mamoru
Asahina Satoru
Amano Reiko
Itou Mamoru
Asahina Satoru
Amano Reiko
Itou Mamoru
Asahina Satoru
Amano Reiko
Itou Mamoru
Asahina Satoru
Amano Reiko
Itou Mamoru
Asahina Satoru
Amano Reiko
Itou Mamoru
Asahina Satoru
Amano Reiko
Itou Mamoru
Asahina Satoru
Amano Reiko
Itou Mamoru
Asahina Satoru
Amano Reiko
Itou Mamoru
Asahina Satoru
Amano Reiko
Itou Mamoru
Asahina Satoru
Amano Reiko
Itou Mamoru
Asahina Satoru
Amano Reiko
Itou Mamoru
Asahina Satoru
Amano Reiko
Itou Mamoru
Asahina Satoru
Amano Reiko
Itou Mamoru
Asahina Satoru
Amano Reiko
Itou Mamoru
Asahina Satoru
Amano Reiko
Itou Mamoru
Asahina Satoru
Amano Reiko
Itou Mamoru
Asahina Satoru
Amano Reiko
Itou Mamoru
Asahina Satoru
Amano Reiko
Itou Mamoru
Asahina Satoru
Amano Reiko
Itou Mamoru
Asahina Satoru
Amano Reiko
Itou Mamoru
Asahina Satoru
Amano Reiko
Itou Mamoru
Asahina Satoru
Amano Reiko
Itou Mamoru
Asahina Satoru
Amano Reiko
Itou Mamoru
Asahina Satoru
Amano Reiko
Episode Two
The Vanishing Children
One month after that, the customary team
ball tournament took place at Sage Academy.
それから １か月後 全人学級で
恒例の搬球トーナメントが
行われることになった
そのルールは ２つの班が
搬球側と妨害側に分かれ
The rules said that two groups will
compete as defenders and attackers.
搬球側は 大きな大理石の球を
転がしてフィールドを運搬し
The attackers roll a big marble sphere over the field
制限時間内にゴールの
穴に落としこめば得点となる
and score should it enter a hole at the end before the clock runs out.
あっ じゃあさ こう
大きな輪っかをこう…
Then how about putting a ring on it like this?
回転させながら進むの
Now it’s easy to push it.
球の方向も
コントロールできるでしょ？
Steering it will be simple, too.
ん～ それだと
But wouldn’t it lose its strength midway?
途中で強度が
足りなくなんじゃねえの？
輪っかを乗り越えちゃうかもよ？
何すんのよ！
What if it rolled past the ring?
Don’t mess with my drawing!
輪っかを全部 接地してるから
回すのは 難しいんじゃないかな
It’d be hard to rotate it without losing contact with the ground.
ちょっと浮いたら
反則になっちゃうよ
They’d penalize us if it went into the air even a little.
あ～あ そっか…
That’s true.
ああ～あ ふんっ
瞬が言うと
簡単に聞きやがんのな
She sure takes criticism easy from Shun.
俺には
いつも突っかかってくんのによ
She would’ve lunged at me instead.
I don’t do that!
そんなことない！
ぐわっ
Oh yes you do!
ある…
ない！
No!
Ow…
イタい…
Although the participants use only their Cantus for the duration of the competition, there is a catch.
競技は終始
呪力のみを使って行われるが
大きな縛りがある
球やフィールドに
直接 呪力を及ぼしてはならない
They aren’t allowed to use their Cantus on the field or the sphere directly.
繰ってもよいのは あくまで
押し子と攻め手
The players can only control either a pusher, an attacker, or a protector.
そして 守り手だけである
いちばん 重要な禁止事項は
The most important rule is that attacking the opponent’s pusher is forbidden.
相手の押し子は
攻撃してはならないこと
ただし 攻撃を免れるのは
However, only the one piece declared as the pusher is safe from attack.
押し子に申告してある
１体だけである
思ったとおりね
いちばん 平凡な作戦だわ
Just as expected.
We can use the simplest plan here.
30秒もかかんねえよ
Won’t even take us thirty seconds.
中央突破しよう
Let’s break through the middle.
It doesn’t matter where we attack, considering their defense.
こんな防御なら
どこから行っても同じだし
真ん中辺りが平らみたいだ
The center area seems bump-free, too.
よし！
いこう！
All right!
Let’s go!
Play fair, work together as a team until the end, and give your all.
お互いに フェアプレイで
最後まで協力し
Group Five   Group One
全力を尽くして いいね？
Got it?
Yes!
はい！
う～ん…
動くまでがシンドイな…
It’s tough to just get it moving.
頑張って！
Do your best!
Center!
中央！
しゃ～！
やった～！
もうちょっと頑張って
欲しかったな～ 張り合いがね～
Man, I wish they would’ve given us a harder time.
I want real enemies.
まだ 向こうの攻撃が
残ってるよ！
We’ve got to defend next! Don’t forget that!
うん 油断は禁物だよ
ヘヘヘ…
Yeah, stay alert.
What is that?
何 あれ？
あ？
６つとも同じ形してるじゃない
All six look the same.
They all chose pushers.
全部 押し子にしたんだ
えっ
攻め手は無しかよ…
They’ve got no attackers.
守ってくれる駒が
なくなっちゃうのに…
Their sphere is defenseless.
頑張れ！
You can do it!
球の勢いで吹っ飛ばす気だ！
They’re trying to break through with their momentum!
まずい！ このままじゃ
Oh no! They’ll make it!
瞬！ 頼むぞ！
Shun! We’re counting on you!
ダメだ！
Oh no!
Group Five   Group One
I declare Group Five unable to continue. Group One shall advance.
５班は 競技続行不能と認めて
１班の勝ちとします
Group Five   Group One
やった！
We did it!
We made it through the first round!
１回戦 突破ね！
楽勝… おっ
Easy as pie!
まずいな…
This looks bad.
どうしたの？
What’s wrong?
There are cracks in it.
ひびが入っちゃった
ええ～
What?
何？
じゃあ これ もう使えないの？
So we can’t use it anymore?
Yeah.
The next time the sphere rolls onto it, it’ll break for good.
たぶん 今度 球が乗ったら
完全に壊れると思う
進路を変える技は もう無理だね
Redirecting the sphere is probably impossible now.
すごい 天才的だよ
エヘ…
You’re really good. A genius.
This idea feels a bit too cheap to me,
あまりにも
セコいアイディアだけど
それだけ 向こうも予想外だろうな
but I bet nobody is expecting this.
セコいけどな
む～
It’s still kinda cheap.
準決勝が終ったわ
The semifinals are over.
どうせ ３班が勝ったんだろ
I bet Group Three won, right?
But hell, we are back in business.
でもな こっちも戦法を見つけたぜ
違うのよ！
３班は 負けちゃったの！
No, no!
Group Three lost.
決勝の相手は ２班よ！
ええ？
We’re facing Group Two in the final.
Final
Group Two                         Group One
こっちが 完全に優勢だったんだ
We were far superior.
How did you lose?
何で 負けちゃったの？
Our pusher and one of their protectors slammed into each other by accident.
事故だったんだけど…
押し子が 向こうの守り手と
思いっきりぶつかっちゃって…
その時
球が 反対側に転がっちゃって
Then the sphere started rolling backwards, and it took us more than a minute to get it back where we were.
元に戻すのに
１分以上 かかったんだ
結局 １分36秒 対 １分41秒で
In the end, it took us 1:41 and them 1:36, so we lost.
２班の勝ちになったの…
Don’t you think that’s unfair?
ひどいと思わない？
It’s their fault if they ram you.
ぶつかってきた 向こうが悪いのに
しかたないよ 事故なんだから…
What can we do?
It was an accident.
気をつけろよ
何が起きるか 分かんないからな
Be careful.
There’s no telling what might happen.
あっ… 見て あれ！
Look!
車輪？
ホント？
Wheels?
Really?
The axle wouldn’t last, though.
車軸が もたねえだろ
That’s why we dropped the idea, right?
だから やめたのよね
Look again.
よく 見て
あれ 車輪じゃなくて 球だ
It’s not a wheel, it’s a sphere.
So they’re just riding the piece on the sphere?
かぶさってるだけなのかな？
すぐ 外れちまうんじゃねえの？
I bet it’s going to fall apart in no time.
これより 決勝戦を行います
Let the final begin.
Final
Group Two                         Group One
頑張れ！ いけ いけ！
頑張れ！
２人がかりで！
Two people…
…are pushing it?!
押してんのか！
頑張れ！
わあ！
ああ… ごめん
Sorry.
We’ve got a problem!
やられた！
もらったな
We did it.
やっちまえ やっちまえ！
どこだ！
あっ…
Where is it?!
どうなってんだよ！
What’s going on?!
ゴールがねえじゃねえか！
The goal’s nowhere to be seen!
ゴールはあるよ
It’s there all right.
It is? Where?
ある？ どこに！
敵に教える筋合いは ないと思うな
I have no obligation to tell my opponent.
おかしいぞ！
おい！ ちょっと 時間 止めろ！
This is messed up!
Hey, stop the time!
ダメよ！ 絶対に止めないで！
No! Don’t stop it!
This isn’t funny!
冗談じゃねえぞ！
How are we supposed to do this if the goal isn’t there?
ゴールがねえのに
どうやって 試合を続けんだ！
探せよ
Find it.
無駄に時間を使えっかよ！
Are you trying to waste our time?
If there really were no goal at all,
we’d be breaking the rules and lose.
あるってば 本当になかったら
こっちの 反則負けにすりゃいいよ
隠したんだな…
You’ve hidden it!
You’re breaking the rules!
反則だぞ！
There’s no rule against hiding it.
隠しちゃダメって ルールは
なかったはずだよ？
フィールドに 手を加えるのは
立派な反則だ！
Changing the battlefield is a clear violation of the rules!
ところが 加えてないんだなあ
ヒント！
Too bad we didn’t do that.
Here’s a hint—
早く探さないと
時間切れになるわよ！
Hurry up or you’ll run out of time!
It’s there!
あれだ！
円盤でゴールの穴 ふさいでる！
They covered the goal with a disc!
そんなの ルール違反だろ
That’s against the rules!
フィールドには 手を加えてない
We haven’t changed the battlefield.
違反じゃないよ
We’ve broken no rules.
Damn it…
くっそ… 良 いくぞ！
Ryou, let’s finish this!
Okay!
よし！
あちゃ～ 壊れちゃった
Oh, it broke…
It has fulfilled its purpose.
使命は 果たしたよ
３分 超えてるって～！
They went over 3 minutes!
これなら 楽勝だな
This should be a walk in the park.
よ～し 行けえ！
All right! Let’s go!
Focus, Mamoru!
守 集中して！
Okay!
情けない声 出さない！
Get your act together!
ありがとう
Thanks.
お礼 言ってる場合じゃないでしょ
Thank me later!
あと少し！
うん
Almost there!
We’ve got this now.
これで 決められる
うん！
Yeah!
っしゃ！ ゴ～！
Okay, go!
What are you doing?
何すんだよ こんな…
This… This…
こんな…
This is too much.
ひどい…
Sorry, that was an accident.
悪い… 事故だ
An accident?
事故？
そんな 言い訳ないでしょう！
Are you kidding me?!
All right!
よ～し！ 時間を止めて
Stop the time.
大変 残念ですが
I regret to say that due to this
unfortunate accident, the finals are a draw.
偶然の事故により
決勝戦は 引き分けにします
そんな！
That’s ridiculous!
こんなの
向こうの反則じゃないですか！
The other team has clearly broken the rules!
いや 今のは 偶然の事故です
No, it was a mere accident.
１班と２班の同時優勝
ということで いいですね？
Let’s just say both groups won.
信じられない 絶対
わざと ぶつかってきたのよ！
I can’t believe this!
I’m sure he did that on purpose!
そうだよ あれは事故じゃない
Yeah, that was no accident.
Group Three had the same thing happen.
３班の時と おんなじ
That bastard Manabu was waiting for the right opportunity.
学のやつ
タイミングを計ってたんだよ
球 すれすれに入って 押し子に
ぶつけるのも 計算通りだよ
He totally intended to smash our pusher just as the sphere was about to go in.
Shun, don’t you agree?
瞬も そう思うだろ？
Come on.
何だよ… あれが事故だったなんて
信じてないよな？
You don’t think it was an accident, do you?
いや… 僕が 気になってるのは
No…
I’m more worried about what happened before that.
むしろ その前なんだ
Before?
前？
The pusher suddenly stopped.
押し子が 急に止まったんだよ
壁か 何かにぶつかったみたいに
It felt like I had hit a wall with it.
えっ？
ホントに？
Huh?
Really?
それ 間違いない？
Are you sure about that?
Yeah.
押し子の感触が 何だか変だった
The pusher just felt so… strange.
フィールドに
特に でこぼこもなかったのに…
The field wasn’t particularly rough either.
That meant someone had stopped our pusher using their Cantus.
だとすれば 誰かが呪力を使って
こちらの 押し子を
止めたとしか 考えられない
While it was already against the rules to use your Cantus directly on the sphere,
球に 直接 呪力を及ぼすことも
反則なら
別の人間が 呪力を
及ぼしている対象に 割り込むのは
interfering with an object someone else was already controlling was a far more serious problem.
それ以前の問題
それは 明白な倫理規定違反
It was a clear violation of the Code of Virtue.
万が一 呪力と呪力が
バッティングすれば
If by chance two Canti clashed, one
would see a rainbow interference pattern.
虹のような干渉模様が現れ
空間がゆがみ
Space would warp, creating a highly dangerous environment.
きわめて 危険な状態となる
つまり ２班には
およそ ルールというルールを
Essentially, someone in Group Two had no qualms breaking even the most fundamental of rules.
踏みにじっても
平気な人間がいることになる
もうすぐ キャンプね
うん
You’ll be having your camp soon.
Yeah.
You haven’t been outside the Holy Barrier since you went to the Temple, right?
八丁標の外に出るのは
お寺に行って以来ね
Yeah.
うん
楽しみでしょ？
You must be looking forward to it.
うん…
機嫌 悪いの？
Yeah.
Are you in a bad mood?
そんなことないよ
Not really.
Oh?
そう？
うん
Yeah.
全人学級で
何か 嫌なことでもあるの？
Did something bad happen at Sage Academy?
How was it back then?
お母さんの頃は？
うん？
Did anything happen with you?
何もなかった？
えっ…
Huh?
なかったの？
Anything?
ないわよ 毎日 勉強してただけよ
Nothing really happened. We just studied a lot.
Is something wrong?
何か あるの？
Not really.
何もないけど…
Inaba Ryou
Katayama Manabu
Kawamata Risa
これは 全人学級でも
大変 重要な行事です
This is a very important event in Sage Academy.
皆さんだけで カヌーに乗り
利根川を逆上ってもらいます
You will all board canoes and row up the Tone River.
そして テントを張りながら
７日間を過ごします
You will spend seven days living in tents.
全ての計画は 皆さんに任されます
Summer Camp
You are free to decide your plans for that time.
We teachers will make sure that your schedules won’t clash.
班ごとの日程が
ぶつからないように
少し 先生の方で
調整はさせてもらいます
これは 殊のほか 大事な実習です
This is an exceedingly important experience for you.
有意義な課題を期待していますよ
We’re expecting great topics from you.
Yessir!
Summer Camp
はい！
あっ！
何？
Oh.
What?
Look, there.
ほら あそこ
バケネズミ？
Queerats?
Mom said they don’t actually exist.
そんなの本当はいないって
お母さんが言ってた
Queerats exist all right.
バケネズミは ちゃんといるよ
ウソ！
ウソじゃない
No way!
They do.
この前の 町の普請にも
A lot of them were brought in to help with construction in the villages recently, too.
バケネズミは
大勢 駆り出されてたしね
I’ve never seen one!
見たことない
We make sure the children don’t see them.
子供の目には
触れないようにしてるんだよ
You’re not scared of them?
怖くないんだ？
Do you know the phrase “rebelling in secret”?
早季は｢面従腹背｣っていう言葉を
知ってるかな？
It means that you appear to obey something, but deep down your opinion is different.
表面は 従っているけど
腹の中では
違うことを考えてるって意味だ
And so you deceive and plot betrayal.
相手をだまし
裏切る計画を立てるんだ
The queerats worship humans with
Cantus as gods and would never disobey,
バケネズミは
呪力を持った人間のことは
神として あがめているから
絶対に服従する
でも まだ呪力のない子供には
どんな態度に出るか
but since children have no Cantus yet, who knows how they would react?
分からないんだよ
For that reason we have to keep
children from meeting the queerats.
だから
子供と バケネズミが出会うことは
避けなきゃならないんだ
何してるんだろ？
What are they doing?
あんまり 見ない方がいいよ
We shouldn’t stare at them for too long.
They’re hard at work.
よく働くなあ～
They seem to be having a hard time working with the nets.
でも 綱を持つのも大変みたい
ホントだね
骨格が 人間とは違うから
Yeah.
Their bodies are structured differently from ours, so
I think just standing upright is already difficult for them.
２本足で立つだけでも
かなり無理してるみたいだし
見ない方がいいって… ねえ
We really shouldn’t stare at them.
あっ！ あぶね！
Hey, watch out!
Help!
ちょっと 早季？
Saki, what—
助ける
I’m helping it.
えっ？ どうやって？
How?
You should leave the queerats alone!
バケネズミには
関わらない方がいいよ
I’ll be fine!
大丈夫！ あそこから持ち上げて
I just need to lift it up and bring it ashore!
こっちに乗せるだけだから 楽勝よ
ダメよ！ 勝手に呪力 使っちゃ！
You shouldn’t use your Cantus without permission!
I agree. You shouldn’t.
僕も やめた方がいいと思う
It will die if we abandon it!
ほっといてたら 死んじゃう！
まわりの葉っぱごと
持ち上げちゃえばいいよ
You should just lift it along with all the leaves.
タス… ケ…
すごいね 完璧な浮揚だったよ
Good work.
That was a perfect Suspension.
瞬こそ
完璧なアドバイスだったわよ
And you gave me perfect advice, Shun.
どうすんだよ 学校にバレたら
What if the school hears about this?
Let’s just hope they never find out.
見つかんなきゃいいじゃない
Never find out?
見つかんなきゃ？
I’m asking about what happens if they do!
もし 見つかったらって
言ってんだよ
Let’s all keep this a secret.
みんな
このことは 絶対に秘密にしましょ
早季のためよ いいわね？
It’s for Saki’s sake. Okay?
いいよ
Sure.
Thank you... Thank you...
アイガト… アイガト
あっ！
G-G-G-G-Gods... Gods...
…サマ カ ヴィーサマ
しゃべってるよ
They’re talking!
What’s your name?
名前 何て言うの？
告げ口の心配はねえな
At least we don’t need to worry about them telling on us.
何 言ってるか わかんねえもんな
It’s not like anybody could understand them.
あっ… 木 619？
Goat 619?
Goat 619
木は たぶん
｢ボクトウガ｣の｢ボク｣だ
It’s probably the “goat” in “goat moth”.
いろんな コロニーが
あるっていうから
There are a lot of colonies. I think it’s one of them.
Goat 619
その名前だと思う
Then they’re workers from the Goat Moth colony?
じゃあ コイツは
ボクトウガコロニーのワーカーか
ヴォクトウガ… ヴェクトウガ…
G-Goat... Moth... C-C-Colony...
チ… コロニー…
寒そう
I think it’s feeling cold.
びしょれだし バケネズミは
It’s soaked, and I hear their body
temperature is already low to begin with.
もともと 体温は低いんだと思うよ
ああ ほらほら
みんな 早く帰らなくちゃ
Hey, hear that? We should head home.
We came to forget the bitter taste the
team ball tournament had left in our mouths,
搬球トーナメントの
後味の悪い 幕切れ
長期欠席を続けていた
天野麗子の名札が外れたこと
and our memory of the long-since
absent Amano Reiko faded as well.
２班で ルール違反を犯した
片山 学が消えたこと
We hardly took note that Katayama Manabu from
Group Two, who broke the rules, had disappeared as well.
皆 ほとんど無関心だった
Maria was born two weeks after me.
真理亜は
私が生まれた２週間後に生まれた
未熟児で
私よりも 深刻な状態だったらしい
She was also born premature, and her condition after birth was even worse than mine.
もし 真理亜が
この世に 生まれてこなかったら
I think if Maria had never been born unto this world,
結果的に あれほど大勢の人が
then untold numbers could have been spared.
命を落とすこともなかったのに…
Nakisou na aoringo kakaeteru mune no oku
泣きそうな青リンゴ  抱えてる胸の奥
In my chest, I carry a green apple that wets my eyes
Korogatte tsuyogatte
転がって  強がって
I fall over yet pretend to be strong
Kyuukutsu na sora niramu
窮屈な空睨む
I glower at the sky and it seems to suffocate me
Unmei ni juujun ni
運命に従順に
Do I look like I'd wait quietly
Jukusu no wo matsu mon ka
熟すのを待つもんか
For destiny to ripen it?
Sen no kaze
千の風
The winds
Agaite sakende
あがいて  叫んで
I struggle and scream
Fuke fuke
吹け吹け
Blow and blow
Watashi wa shabondama
わたしはしゃぼん玉
I'm a soap bubble
Soredemo shinjiteru
それでも信じてる
And still I have faith
Yokisenu arashi ni
予期せぬ  嵐に
In a sudden storm
Joushou shite kakou shite
上昇して  下降して
I rise and fall
Aragau shabondama
あらがうしゃぼん玉
I fight, soap bubble that I am
Soredemo ikiteku
それでも生きてく
And still I live on
Hajikeru shunkan niji hanate
弾ける瞬間  虹、放て
I make a rainbow when I burst
FROM
THE
NEW
WORLD
Episode Three
The False Minoshiro
あの話だったら たぶんウソだって
I don’t think that part of the story is true.
Are we going to die?
私たち… 死ぬのかしら？
アンタは誰？ 一体 何なの
Who are you? What are you?